Guide to the June Rovenger Photograph Collection 1970's, 2000's PR 291
New-York Historical Society
June Rovenger Photograph Collection
circa 1970's, 2000's
New-York Historical Society
Rovenger, June, 1933-2012
PR 291
0.54 Linear feet (2 boxes)
This collection consists of photographs of Harlem, Greenwich Village, and street fairs and other events in New York City.
Biographical note
June Rovenger (1933-2012) was a New York City theater director. She directed a number of off-Broadway productions from the 1960's to the 1990's, including Shakespeare's Richard III, Eugene O'Neil's Beyond the Horizon, and The Rivals by Richard Brinsley Sheridan.
Rovenger was also an amateur photographer, and in her later years took photography classes at the International Center for Photography (where Amy Arbus was one of her instructors) and the Education Alliance. From the 1960's until her death, she lived in a rent-controlled apartment on Commerce Street; her tiny bathroom could be converted into a darkroom where she developed her own prints. She photographed many actors and performers, as well as street scenes in Harlem and her own West Village neighborhood.
Scope and Contents
The June Rovenger Photograph Collection consists of approximately 300 black and white photographic prints, along with a few color photos, contact sheets and negatives. The photographs include portraits and street scenes in Harlem in the 1970's; street fairs, snow scenes and protests in the West Village in the 2000's; and portraits of children. A few of the contact sheets are marked with comments, presumably from one of Rovenger's photograph class instructors.
Provenance
Gift of Micaela Walker, 2012
Access restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Arrangement
This collection has been organized into the following two series:
Series I: Photographic prints (8 x 10 inches and smaller), contact sheets and negatives
Series II: Photographic prints (11 x 13 inches)
Harlem (New York, N.Y.); Parades -- New York (State) -- New York.; Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.
- Series I: Photographic prints (8 x 10 inches and smaller), contact sheets and negatives
  - Harlem, 1970's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Snow scenes, Barrow Street, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bedford-Barrow-Commerce Street Fair, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cherry Lane Theater, 2001 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Zito's Bakery, 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mermaid Parade, 2007 June (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rican Day parade, undated (circa 2000's) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Protest of St. Vincent Hospital closing, 2010 April (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Halloween, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Skateboarding, undated (circa 2000's) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Children, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bottles and trash, 2005, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photos of June Rovenger, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Views from Rovenger's Commerce Street apartment (color), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified street fair (color), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Photographic prints (11 by 13 inches)
  - Harlem (children), 1970''s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Harlem (adults), 1970's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Harlem (dogs and trash), 1970's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Children, undated (circa 2000's) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mermaid Parade, 2007 June (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)